WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.
Oh, heavens.
This is nice. It's from Gwen.
She's married.
Who's Gwen? She used to work as a
housemaid here.
She left to be a secretary.
That's her ladyship for you, Miss
Braithwaite.
She says they kept it very quiet
because his mother's ill
but she hopes she can introduce us to
him in due course.
Well, I think it's lovely.
We should send her a card. I'll get
one and we can all sign it.
Sorry. I nearly forgot this.
No harm done.
How are you finding it? Have that
lot got used to your promotion yet?
Some of them. But not all, eh?
I'll be fine. I don't need to have
everyone love me.
Nor me. Which is just as well...
Miss Braithwaite?
I hope you don't mind
but can I give you some advice?
Go on. Mr Barrow never bothered with you
when you were a housemaid but he will now.
I should be friendly but keep him at
arms length if I were you.
I'd better get on.
What do you think's in it?
I cannot say, James.
It's addressed to Lady Mary so
perhaps you could question HER later?
Mr Carson?
You see the box has been delivered
from the late Mr Crawley's office? Yes.
Well, ought we to give it straight to Lady
Mary? Shouldn't someone else see it first?
In case there's something in it
to make her cry.
You may be right. I'll take it to
his lordship and he can decide.
I say. Phyllis Dare's coming to the
Theatre Royal in York.
Miss Dare will appear in The Lady Of The Rose
which was a hit musical of the London season.
Who's Phyllis Dare?
Only one of the Dare sisters.
Zena and Phyllis Dare Up here in
York.
What happened to the other one. She
married the son of Lord Esher then retired.
Oh, all right for some!
Have you truly never heard of them?
Why would I? I don't go to the theatre.
You must have been sometimes?
No, I've never been.
She's got better things to spend her
money on.
I don't understand you. Of course
you must give it to her.
But what if it has no legal status?
I don't want to build her hopes up
only to have them dashed.
Robert, Matthew intended Mary to be
his sole heiress.
That will mean a great deal to her
whether or not it's legal.
Can't you see that?
But is it right to exclude George?
Well, right or not,
it is what he wanted.
Besides, it's not up to you.
I'll send it to Murray.
Well, Mary must read it before you
send it anywhere.
Or are you trying to hide from the
truth?
What truth?
That you would prefer to be in sole charge of
the estate and not share the crown with Mary.
Don't be silly. This won't make any
difference to all that.
She won't want to get involved.
When you talk like that, I'm tempted
to ring for Nanny and have you put
to bed with no supper.
Goodbye, Mr Grigg.
Thank you, Doctor.
All he needs to put him right
is some paid work.
It's hard for a healthy young man to
find a job these days, never mind
poor old Mr Grigg.
I know. Thank you.
But Mrs Crawley has things in hand.
My guess is that you knew what you
were doing bringing him here.
Mrs Hughes? Won't you come up?
Oh, don't get up for me.
What news of Charlie? Mr Carson is still
very busy but he sends his best wishes.
Does he?
How did he phrase that exactly?
Well, he... He said to tell you -
He didn't say nothing, did he?
You have to understand, he doesn't
remember the days you spent
together with any great nostalgia.
He thinks it were all my fault...
but it weren't.
Meaning what?
Never mind.
But it weren't my fault.
They're all coming tonight so we
have to stretch a dinner by two places.
Why, suddenly?
I don't know, do I?
Go on about Jimmy. I just want Ivy
to know he's not interested in her.
He pretends he is because he knows
it annoys me. How can you be so sure?
He hasn't been bothered about her
before now, has he?
Sometimes people come around.
You hope.
I thought the fish seller might be
in the village but he's not coming.
I'll have to go to Tuttles in York.
I can do it.
What? Go to York. You can tell Mr
Carson I'm there on your business.
We don't know he can spare you.
He will if YOU ask him.
Hello, Mr Molesley.
How are things? Well, as you can see,
not very good.
I don't agree. It's skilled work.
No, it isn't, not what I'm doing.
I'm sure if you just wait something
better will turn up.
I have waited
and nothing's turned up.
I haven't earned a penny since Mr Crawley died
and now I owe money all over the village.
Yes, but surely with your -
Don't you understand? I'm at my wits' end!
I apologise. I should not have said
that. It was vulgar and
self-important. Please, forgive me.
How much do you owe?
What difference does it make? 15, 20
pounds.
More than I've any likelihood of.
Mr Molesley...
would it be useful if Mr Bates and I
lent you some money?
When would I pay it back?
Give it, then.
We'll give you some, if you like.
Not much but...but some.
I couldn't accept that...
..but I thank you, I do, most
sincerely.
Get back to work!
Anna said you wanted to see me
before I go down.
Yes. That is...
Thank you, Bates, that will be all.
You know I've invited Granny
and Isobel to dinner. I didn't but -
Well, the thing is...
There is a letter for you from
Matthew.
What? Where was it?
Hidden in a book in the office and
so it was overlooked.
They finally got round to packing up his
things and brought them here this morning.
Who opened it?
It wasn't sealed.
But you've read it before me? Yes.
I would have sent it to Murray to
have it looked into
but your grandmother insisted you
should see it first.
Granny's read it too? And what do
you mean, 'To have it looked into?'
Read it. Then you'll understand.
I felt so sorry for him. To be in
debt like that is the worst thing.
Molesley's not having much luck.
But if he won't accept help then...
I don't know.
I'm really upset by it.
Well, we can't have that.
I don't understand.
Did Matthew leave instructions after
all?
He left a letter. He wrote it before
we went to Scotland.
Well, where has it been? Concealed
in a book. They only dropped off today.
Papa, you read it.
My darling Mary, we are off to
Duneagle in the morning
and I have suddenly realised that I've
never made a will or anything like one,
which seems pretty feeble for a
lawyer and you being pregnant makes
it even more irresponsible.
Hm, I'm afraid I have to agree with
that.
I'll do it properly when I get back
and tear this up before you ever see it
but I'll feel easier that I've
recorded on paper that I wish YOU to
be my sole heiress.
What?
I cannot know if our baby is a boy
or a girl but I do know it will be a baby,
if anything happens to me before
I've drawn up a will
and so you must take charge.
And now I shall sign this and get
off home for dinner with you.
What a lovely, lovely thought.
Matthew.
Now you see
why I didn't want to read it.
But surely it must be legal or do
there have to be witnesses?
But it was witnessed by two of his
clients, which is why no-one in the
office knew it existed.
Then it's settled. Nothing is
settled.
This is why I wanted Murray to check
it first.
Whatever Matthew's intentions, it is
not a will.
I've explained to Mr Carson about
the fish and he says you can go.
Thanks.
A pound to a penny he's got some
trick up his sleeve. You're so suspicious.
There are two reasons why he's being
so nice to Ivy.
The first is to make me angry and I
dread to think about the second.
And I have my reason for getting
THAT to the dining room before midnight.
I don't exactly know why but I feel
very happy that Matthew's been
allowed a last word.
I agree, more than I can say.
I knew he'd have a sensible plan.
I'm not sure how sensible it is.
If the letter is valid, the estate
will have to pay death duties twice
before it reaches little George.
But in the meantime it will have all
the benefit of Mary's interest.
I hope you intend to get stuck in.
I want the right to an opinion. I
shall be content with that.
You already have a right to an
opinion. Do I? Good.
Most certainly you do. In fact,
there's a question of using empty
farmyards as new sources of revenue.
I'd like to know what you feel about
that.
Well, I'd have to think about it -
Crop rotation, livestock versus cereals,
or indeed the whole matter of the tax.
There are lots of things I would
like your opinion on.
I assume you're trying to make some
sort of point?
He's trying to show that a woman's
place is in the home.
But she knows a lot about Matthew's
plans.
That has value for me.
Mrs Crawley, what do you think?
I'm afraid I'm on Mary's side,
Robert, if sides there must be.
There are no sides, not at all. I'm
pleased if you're pleased. I'm just
saying YOU have some work to do.
That is IF the letter turns out to
be valid.
Which you very much hope it is not.
What's the matter with you?
I'm a stupid fool, that's what.
Oh, lordy.
How did you manage that?
Daydreaming. I don't know what I
was about. She'll be livid.
Not if you do as I tell you. Come
on.
By the way did you get that card
For Gwen? Yes, why?
I thought it'd be nice for people in
the village to sign it.
The Bakewells, Mr Molesley, that
sort of thing.
I'll collect them. You surprise me.
Why?
I never think of you as social.
Why should I be social,
when I have you?
You wrote to the Opera House in
Belfast?
That was enterprising.
I wrote to a great many theatres.
But the manager at the Opera House
wrote back.
It seems they're in need of a
stage door keeper.
They'd chosen one but he dropped
out. He asks Mr Grigg to consider it.
I heard about Mr Matthew's letter.
I hope it wasn't too upsetting.
As a matter of fact, it was a
relief.
I felt so happy that he'd finally
been heard
but judging by tonight's dinner, it
may prove a heavy mantle for Lady Mary.
I shall keep it on my dressing table
to remind me that Matthew is on my side.
They're all on your side.
Papa gave me such a whacking at
dinner.
Your father loves you very much.
He's also very glad to have Downton
back under his control.
He always speaks highly of Mr
Matthew and the changes he made.
I'm sure he is very genuine but he
thinks he can manage alone now
and the question is, can he?
You wanted to borrow a belt, m'lady?
Lady Mary wondered if any of these
might suit?
Thank you.
Actually, I'm glad that you're here
as there's something I want to ask.
Look what I found in the village
today.
Don't you think it would be the most
terrific fun?
Have you asked her ladyship?
She'd never let me go, at least not
without a chaperone but Lady Edith
will be in London
and Lady Mary's not in the mood.
But is this quite suitable? It looks
more like something for servants and
farmworkers to me.
So? They'll dance the one-step,
won't they?
I've practiced and practiced and I'm
dying to try it.
Won't you accompany me?
Then if we're found out, I can say
that you came with me so nothing was amiss.
Of course I can't, m'lady, not
without asking Lady Mary.
But that would spoil everything.
She'd be bound to tell Lady Grantham.
Please? I know you love dancing
and Mr Bates may have many qualities
but he's not a dancer.
No, m'lady, he isn't a dancer...
but I'm afraid its quite impossible.
But how did it happen?
I don't like to say, m'lady.
I am truly vexed. It was a
favourite.
I know, m'lady, and I'm very sorry.
But you won't tell me how you did it.
I can't.
Very well, Braithwaite. I suppose
you'd better look me out another.
What are you doing? I'm just sorting some old
papers. I haven't looked at these in years.
Why are you looking now?
No particular reason.
Ah. I knew I hadn't thrown it away.
Who was she? Just a friend at one
time.
What was she called?
Alice. Alice Neal.
And you were fond of her? I was but
people drift in and out of your
life, don't they?
Truth to tell, I felt she'd treated
me badly.
What does it matter anyway?
We shout and scream and wail and cry
but in the end we must all die.
Well, that's cheered me up!
Thank you. Now I'll get on with my
work.
Your ladyship, Mr Bates.
Bates?
I am very sorry to interrupt you
when you're busy, m'lady.
It concerns Mr Molesley the younger.
You make him sound like a Greek
philosopher.
He has fallen on hard times and I
know that YOU have helped him in the past.
Are you asking me to give him some
money?
I am asking for money, yes. Although
he's too proud to accept it as a gift.
Oh, how refreshing.
Although I think we can find a way.
Morning, Barrow.
Good morning, m'lady.
Is his lordship in the library?
He is but erm...
What is it?
Miss Braithwaite is very unhappy.
With good reason.
Yes, but you see...
she couldn't explain how it happened because,
well, she didn't want to point the finger.
Point the finger at whom?
Well, that's just it, m'lady,
I dare not either.
I'm in enough trouble with Mr Bates
as it is.
You're not saying Bates is to blame?
Not Mr Bates himself, no.
Anna, then, but why would she do
such a thing?
As to that, m'lady, who knows?
Perhaps it was an accident.
Though they do say there's no-one so
jealous as a lady's maid.
Cora, is that you?
Could I ask you something?
Where's my scent? Here you are,
m'lady.
Oh!
How stupid of me.
That was my clumsiness.
No, it was me.
Damn! Now the room's going to smell
like a tart's boudoir.
I'll clean it up.
Is it all gone?
I'm afraid so.
It means a trip to Mr Roberts.
There's no-one nearer who sells it here.
It's only York.
I could go, if you like.
In fact...
What?
Lady Rose asked me if I'd chaperone
her to a the dansant in York today.
She didn't want to ask her ladyship
but she thought she'd get away with
it if I went with her.
And what did you say? That I couldn't
go without your permission.
Well, it is rather slow here for a
girl her age.
Go but make sure you keep her out of
trouble.
Go on. I know Gwen'd appreciate it.
I don't see why. I didn't know her
that well.
But you can sign it, surely?
And why don't you come over tonight?
We haven't seen you in a while.
You're very friendly.
Aren't I usually friendly?
No. You're not discourteous,
Mr Bates, I'll give you that
but you're not friendly, except to
Anna, of course.
Well, I shall try to do better
in future.
See you tonight.
Mr Branson, Your ladyship.
Sorry if I'm late. I had to call on
old Fairclough at Roundhills.
You're not at all late.
Now I asked Branson to come here
because I have an idea.
Granny, you must call him Tom.
I thought I could call him Branson
again now that he's the agent.
Well, you can't. I don't mind.
No. I see I'm beaten but, oh, how I
sympathise with King Canute.
Now what is this idea?
Well, Mary, either YOU or your baby
son own half of Downton.
I want you to have a say in the
running of it.
It's just what you need.
But didn't last night's dinner
disabuse you of that scheme?
Well, that's the point. I want er...
Tom. TOM to be your instructor.
What? Well, take Mary, you know,
on your rounds.
Let her learn the farmers'
difficulties.
Mmm.
Explain the crops and the live,
the livestock.
You know, let her see the problems
facing the estate.
And are we to do all this without
telling Papa?
Isn't that rather underhand?
There can be too much truth in any
relationship.
Mrs Crawley.
We weren't expecting you.
Her ladyship is lunching with Lady
Ingram, his lordship is walking,
Lady Mary's at the Dower House and
Lady Edith is in London.
As a matter of fact,
it's YOU I came to see.
To talk about Charles Grigg. You know he's
got a job at the Opera House in Belfast.
He's so anxious to talk to you
before he goes.
Then he is in for a disappointment.
He says he is resolved to put his
dishonesty behind him.
Is he now?
I know it's more than that.
He told me he'd caused you great
unhappiness but he said it was not
his fault.
He was always a liar.
I see.
It seems a pity not to take the
chance to end a quarrel.
Isn't it better than to let things
fester?
I don't mean to speak out of turn,
Mrs Crawley,
but you will, I think, accept that
any difference between Mr Grigg and
me is my concern.
Of course it is.
I'm sorry.
Thank you, Carson.
Good day.
Shall I make us some coffee?
You are so domesticated.
No, not really.
Monk just lays it all out. I only
have to pour in the water.
I mean it. Compared to Papa you're a
famous chef.
Really. He can't boil a kettle.
If the servants left, he'd be found
in a passage, dead, arms stretched
out looking for the kitchen.
Well, I hope you can boil a kettle.
Life with me won't be quite what
you're used to.
How are things going? Ah, well, at
least my lawyer thinks so.
Are you sure about this?
The Royal Family convulses the
nation by ceasing to be German and
you want to take it up.
Does it matter that people will hate
you for it?
Will you hate me? I will love you
more than ever.
That's all right, then. I'm pretty
tough.
I may not be used to the splendours of Downton
but I do know how to look after myself.
Would you like to see Downton?
Where did that come from?
Well, I was thinking if you are
nearly German and nearly divorced,
perhaps the family should know you a
bit.
It won't be settled tomorrow, my
darling, I can't pretend it will.
Don't put me off.
Aren't you curious about my
childhood home?
I'm curious about everything to do
with you.
BUT my situation would frighten them
and we don't want that.
I know. Mama's giving a house party
next month. Why don't you come?
Then you can blend in and look
around
without anyone asking too many questions
and Mama won't mind, she likes you.
But your father doesn't.
He doesn't know you.
He'll like you when he does.
Now, I must gulp my coffee down and
run if I'm to catch the three o'clock.
I can't persuade you to stay?
But, I will say this, it's getting
harder and harder to say no.
Oh, look, we'll take that table.
I'm not sure we should be here,
m'lady. It seems unsuitable to me.
Don't call me m'lady, call me Rose.
I can't!
Well, then don't call me anything.
Seen her down there?
Yes?
Well, it is a the dansant, let's have
a cup of tea. All right, tea.
Oh, but perhaps with something
special in mine? Right you are, Miss.
Listen! It's the one-step!
Oh, why are they being so slow?
Really, m'lady. You mustn't be so
obvious. Why not? It's working.
I don't suppose you'd care to dance?
Then you'd be wrong because I'd
absolutely love to.
Shouldn't we be introduced?
The name's Sam Thawley. How do?
I'm Rose...Smith.
Hello. I hope you know how to do
this.
You're in luck. They call me Twinkle
Toes.
Hello, Anna. Jimmy, What are you
doing here?
I was just picking up some things for
Mrs Patmore. Shall we dance?
We'd better, if only to check Lady
Rose isn't getting in too deep.
I'm under gardener for Lord Ellis
near Easingwold. What about you?
I'm at... I'm at Downton Abbey.
Oh, yeah? What do you do? Are you a
lady's maid?
You sound posh enough.
Do I? I'm so pleased. I've...
I've worked and worked on my accent.
Ah, you've done well. You could pass
for a real lady never mind a lady's maid.
I'm not a lady's maid yet. Anna is,
the girl I'm with, but I wonder if
I'm clever enough.
Ah, well, you won't be a housemaid
forever. I expect you've got a few
young farmers hanging about.
I couldn't say.
You won't say, you mean.
James? How how how did you find us?
I saw you across the square, m'lady.
Rose was saying what fun it is to be
out like this.
I thought I'd pop in to see what the
craic was.
It's a good craic, isn't it, Sam?
Well, it is with you in my arms.
I love the view from up here.
If you know the view, all the
better.
Follow that hedge.
To the left of it is Oakwood Farm,
to the right is all farmed by us.
Do we want to take over Oakwood
Farm? No.
The Olds are good tenants and hard
workers.
Mm.
There is one subject we ought to
discuss.
I know your position isn't settled
but we should. Go on.
The death duties. If you are the
heir, it won't change them.
There's no special treatment for
widows. You do not surprise me.
It seems odd, really, that you have
to pay just as much tax
as if he'd left it all to Mrs
Tiggywinkle down the road.
Mm. But that's how it works.
So, what are we to do?
Your father believes we should sell
land and pay it off in one lump.
But you don't?
I want to know what you think.
I've some good tickets for me and
Ivy.
To see Phyllis Dare? I don't believe
you.
Well, I have. It cost a packet and
no mistake.
Does Ivy know? Not yet.
Mate, let's have a dance, eh?
Sorry, I'm dancing with her. I said
let her dance with me.
I don't want to dance with you.
How do you know if you've not even
tried it?
Don't tell me you're falling for her
at last? She will be pleased.
I said leave her alone.
That's the idea.
Out the way! Come on, then.
Sam are you OK?
Get off me. Get off my hand!
Get off him! Sam! Get off! Get off!
Sam! Get her out of here!
Get off him! Come here, you.
James!
I can't leave when he's fighting to
protect me.
You can, or do you want to be
arrested?
We need to get out of here.
That settles it.
Come on! Go, go, go!
Mr Molesley, is that you? Come in
and have a cup of tea.
Mr Bates thought I might be welcome.
And so you are. Sit down.
Mr Molesley, I'm glad you're here.
I was going through my desk this
afternoon
and I came upon that note of mine
and, er, if you're willing, I'd like
to pay it off now.
What note? Well, you lent me some
money when I was first came here
and I'm sorry I haven't paid it back before
now but the truth is I'm afraid I forgot.
I don't remember anything about it.
£30! Aren't you the lucky one!
Surely there must be some mistake?
You'll not deny that's your
signature Plain as day.
How was your trip to York?
Never mind that, what's going on?
Mr Bates has remembered he owed £30
to Mr Molesley. What?
But, but, but, no er...
There you are and thank you for
coming to my aid when I needed it.
Now, I must go. I have some things
to do before his lordship comes up.
Thank you, Mr Molesley.
Mr Carson, can I have a word?
Certainly, James.
Why did you do that?
You have put up with so much that I
couldn't change
so if there is ever the slightest thing
I can make better for you, then I will.
But how did you manage it? Don't I
keep telling you? Prison was an education.
Take her to the theatre?
It is my half day.
But not hers and how do we know
she'd want to go. She'll want to go.
She could change her half day.
Oh, I don't know.
It's turning into Liberty Hall round
here.
Are we entertaining that night?
I'm not cooking. They'll all be
dining with Lady Lawson at Brough Hall.
Very well but no lingering.
You can go and give her the good
news. Thank you, Mr Carson.
I hope he doesn't break her heart.
We must all have our hearts broken
once or twice before we're done.
True enough, Mrs Hughes.
Strange to think the theatre was
part of my life at one time.
Yours and Mr Griggs.
You know he's going to work in
Belfast?
I had heard. He's leaving the
village in the morning.
The 11 o'clock train.
What's that to me?
I'll tell you what it is. It's an
open wound.
I don't know why but I do know this:
You'd do better to stitch it up
and let it heal.
I'm sorry, m'lord, I didn't hear the
gong. It's all right. It hasn't gone yet.
I was hoping to catch you.
Of course I understand how tiresome
it must have been for Anna
when Edna came back and was suddenly
the senior lady's maid.
M'lord? Ask her to go easy.
I'm sorry, m'lord, but I don't
understand what you're saying.
Her ladyship appears to think
there's been some bad feeling
between Braithwaite and Anna.
That Anna has been a little unkind.
Not that I know of.
Look, I don't want to make a thing
of it. I'm just asking for a little
consideration, that's all.
And you shall have it, m'lord.
Good. That's all I needed to hear.
Ah, there's the gong now.
I just can't believe you're letting
me go. Do you really mean it?
No, I was having you on.
Oh, don't be so soft. I've said you
can go and you can go.
What should I wear? Clothes.
But I haven't got anything right.
Not for the theatre in York.
It's not Covent Garden.
What? Oh, never mind. We'll make you
look presentable.
Now get that parsley!
I don't know why she's so excited.
It's only a bloomin' play.
He's just as keen on her as ever.
We'll see. Nothing's as changeable
as a young man's heart.
Take hope and a warning from that.
I'll get it.
Yes? I was wondering if I could have
a word with the housemaid Rose.
The housemaid Rose? The maid Rose
who works here.
Look, chum. I'll deal with it, Mr
Barrow.
Hello, Mr Thawley.
Well, I'll leave you to it.
I've got to know she's all right.
Rose is a bit busy just now but I'll
tell her you asked.
I don't mind waiting.
Can I er... Can I come in?
If you'll just stay there, I'll...
I'll see what she's up to.
Anna? What? What is it?
The man you were dancing with, Sam
Thawley, he's downstairs.
But why? What what does he want?
He says he's come to make sure that
you're all right.
What have you done with him? Left him in the
yard before he asks the others any questions.
But what can I say? What can I do?
Come with me. I've got an idea.
This is so very kind of you.
I had to come.
You know, I had to see that you were
...er, you know, all right after
that ruckus.
And I...and I am, thanks to you.
I never saw anything so brave as the
way you punched that horrid man.
I'd do more than that for you.
How very flattering.
Where did you grow up? You don't
sound very Yorkshire.
Don't I? That's...
that's because my life's been sort of
spent all over the place.
North, south, east, west...
Home's the place that I love best.
What?
That's how the song goes.
Yes, I...I suppose it is.
Would you let me call on you again?
Well... Look, I know I'm not good
enough for you, I can see that
but I'm a steady chap, ask Lord
Ellis's agent.
He'd give me a good reference. I'm
sure but it's...it's something else.
Do you remember wondering if any of
the local farmers were after me?
Yeah. Well, that's the thing, I...
There is one farmer and I didn't want
to spoil this afternoon by mentioning it
but I have rather given him my word.
Well, that's me back in my box,
then. I hope you understand.
Course I do. He's a lucky bloke,
that's all I'll say.
Well, good luck, then.
It's been nice knowing you.
You too.
Mr Thawley? Sam?
When you do find someone, someone
much nicer and better than I am...
..she'll be a very lucky girl.
What the - Say nothing and I'll be
your friend forever.
Is Lord Grantham in the drawing
room? Yes, m'lady. Thank you.
Ah, here she is.
Oh, darling. Ah, are you only just
back?
We sat forever outside Peterborough.
We never found out why.
Shall I change?
No, don't bother. It's only us.
And who are we to warrant any
courtesy? Don't be difficult, Granny.
Where's Rose? Have we lost her?
I'm so sorry I'm late.
Never mind, never mind.
Now I've got you all here, and before
Carson comes in, I have something to say.
I had a letter today from Murray.
Wait just a moment while I finish.
Shall I leave, my lord?
No. You might as well hear this.
Murray has taken Matthew's letter to
various authorities
and their conclusion is that it
demonstrates testamentary intention.
What's that?
It means that the writer intended
the document to serve as a will.
So, the bequest stands? Yes. Mary
owns half the estate.
That sounds like a very good result.
And now we should go into dinner
before Mrs Patmore blows a gasket.
Dearest Papa, I hope you're not too
disappointed.
Don't be silly. Not at all.
Perhaps the three of us can sit down
tomorrow and talk properly.
Of course but the main problem is a
simple one: tax.
But that's it, Tom's told me you
want to sell land to pay for it.
It's the only way, I'm afraid.
Yes, but, you see, I don't agree.
Anyway, let's not talk about it now.
We ought to join the others.
If you've put her up to this...
I haven't put her up to anything but
you won't keep her quiet, not now
the bit's between her teeth.
Don't think that you will.
I don't know what he meant.
You must have said something.
But I haven't said anything.
I warned her off Mr Barrow, that's
all, but I wasn't having a go at her.
All I can tell you is that she has
managed to take offence.
She can't have.
Mr Barrow, what are you doing down
here?
Will you come up this moment and
help me serve the wine?
Sorry, Mr Carson, I'm on my way.
What's so funny?
Nothing, Mr Bates.
Nothing at all.
Good morning, Carson.
I hope I'm not in the way.
Not a bit. You remember Mr Grigg?
Hello, Charlie. Good of you to come.
I'm delighted but I'm not surprised.
Aren't you? Because I'm astonished.
But why did you never speak of Alice
when we last met before the war?
What was the point? She chose you
all those years ago and that was it.
Why bring it up?
Because it wasn't IT.
She chose me but it never worked.
She's dead now, anyway,
but it was never IT.
I didn't know she was dead.
Five year ago.
We'd separated long before but I
went to see her in St Thomas's.
Do you know what she said?
She said, 'Charlie Carson was the
better man. I could have loved him.
I did love him, really, but I was a
fool and couldn't see it.'
Did she say that? Honestly?
That she loved you? Aye, she did
and she wanted me to tell you,
if I saw you again.
There we are. We could have made a
go of it, you know.
As long as you know that it were her
choice. I never set out to take her off you.
All aboard!
I am sorry to interrupt but I think
you must get aboard.
I can't tell you how grateful I am,
Mrs Crawley. Very good luck.
Thank you.
I doubt we'll meet again
but can we shake on it?
We've known some ups and downs
together, it's true,
but if this is goodbye...
let's part as friends, eh?
All right.
I wish you well. Likewise...
..Charlie.
Mrs Crawley, I should be grateful
if you would let me know any expense
you have been put to on Mr Griggs'
behalf during his stay with you.
Oh, no. That's completely
unnecessary. I should be grateful.
Very well, Carson, I shall do that.
Good day to you.
Mr Carson?
Shall we walk back together?
I gather the Abbey is once more to
be a scene of great splendour.
Who's the glamorous pirate?
Johnnie Gillingham's son.
Stick it under my arm, if you can.
You're an angel from above.
I don't know about that.
Is there anyone who wants to dance?
What about it? How can grown
men throw away their fortune like
that? What could be more stupid?
There's something about him that gets
my goat. He was just trying to be nice.
I don't want them to spend
It seems disloyal to Matthew.
Screaming in the servants' halls.
What a topsy-turvy world we've come to.
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.